Sarah Owens Collection of Postal Ephemera PC.5318
State Archives of North Carolina
Sarah Owens Collection of Postal Ephemera
1971-1976
PC.5318
FOLDER
0.200
This collection consists of first day covers and other commemorative stamps issued by the United States Postal Service in honor of significant events in the nation's history. These items primarily relate to topics of historical significance to the Outer Banks of North Carolina and were collected by Manteo resident Sarah Alford Owens from 1971 to 1976.
Owens, Sarah Frances Alford, 1937-2015
United States Postal Service
Outer Banks History Center
Box Box 1
Gift
Arrangement
Chronological.
Access Restrictions
Available for research.
Biographical/Historical
Sarah Frances (Alford) Owens was born 19 February 1937 in Manteo, North Carolina, to Edwin Joseph Alford (1899-1937) and Cora Mae Daniels (1910-1998). She had one older brother, Edwin Joseph Alford, Jr. (1930-2005), and several younger siblings: Dotty Basnight Fry, Sally Basnight Scarborough, Della Basnight, Saint Basnight, Jr., and Marc Basnight. She married Robert Valentine "Bobby" Owens 8 September 1956 and had two children: Robert Valentine Owens, III (born 1957), and Lisa Sterling (Owens) Hooper (1960-2007). During her lifetime, Sarah performed in The Lost Colony, served with the Manteo Woman's Club, and volunteered with the Dare County Arts Council. She collaborated with photographer Aycock Brown to promote tourism to the Outer Banks in the mid-20th century.
Sarah Owens
Custodial History
Formerly classified as 33EPH-117
Provenance
Donated by Sarah Owens.
Scope and Content
The Sarah Owens Collection of Postal Ephemera, 1971-1976, primarily consists of first day covers and other commemorative stamps issued by the United States Postal Service in honor of significant events in the nation's history. These items primarily relate to topics of historical significance to the Outer Banks of North Carolina, such as the Cape Hatteras National Seashore and the Wright Brothers' first flight. In addition to stamps, several programs from celebratory events are included. These materials were collected by Sarah Owens.
United States Postal Service
Commemorative postage stamps--United States; Covers (philately)--North Carolina
- First Day of Issue US Airmail Nine Cent Stamp, 15 May 1971; 113428; 33EPH-117-6; 5000.3.557.6; Envelope(s); Owens, Sarah Frances Alford, 1937-2015; NA (Folder First Day of Issue US Airmail Nine Cent Stamp)
  Gift
  Sarah Owens
  Scope and Content
  envelope publicizes The First Flight Society
- First Day of Issue Ceremony Nine Cent Air Mail Post Card and Nine Cent Air Mail Postage Stamp, 15 May 1971; 113432; 33EPH-117-11; 5000.3.557.10; Programs; Owens, Sarah Frances Alford, 1937-2015; NA (Folder First Day of Issue Ceremony Nine Cent Air Mail Post Card and Nine Cent Air Mail Postage Stamp)
- First Day of Issue Nine Cent Air Mail Postal Card and Nine Cent Air Mail Stamp Ceremony Program, Kitty Hawk, North Carolina, 15 May 1971; 209278; Owens, Sarah Frances Alford, 1937-2015 (Folder First Day of Issue Nine Cent Air Mail Postal Card and Nine Cent Air Mail Stamp Ceremony Program, Kitty Hawk, North Carolina)
- Official First Day Card Nine Cent Airmail Stamp, 15 May 1971; 113423; 33EPH-117-1; 5000.3.557.1; Envelope(s); Owens, Sarah Frances Alford, 1937-2015; NA (Folder Official First Day Card Nine Cent Airmail Stamp)
  Post Card shows "monument of First Flight 12/17/1903, at the time of First Sep on the Moon 07/20/1969"
- First Day of Issue Inaugurating the US Postal Service, 1 July 1971; 113430; 33EPH-117-8; 5000.3.557.8; Envelope(s); Owens, Sarah Frances Alford, 1937-2015; NA (Folder First Day of Issue Inaugurating the US Postal Service)
- The National Parks Centennial Stamps, 5 January 1972; 113434; 33EPH-117-13; 5000.3.557.12; Pamphlets; Owens, Sarah Frances Alford, 1937-2015; NA (Folder The National Parks Centennial Stamps)
- First Day of Issue Cape Hatteras National Park Envelope and National Parks Centennial Stamps, 5 April 1972; 113425; 33EPH-117-3; 5000.3.557.3; Envelope(s); Owens, Sarah Frances Alford, 1937-2015; NA (Folder First Day of Issue Cape Hatteras National Park Envelope and National Parks Centennial Stamps)
  envelope show Bodie Island Lighthouse as "Oregon Juliet Lighthouse", an explanation inside the envelope states perhaps the error will make the envelope a collectors item one day
- First Day of Issue National Park Centennial Stamps, 5 April 1972; 113429; 33EPH-117-7; 5000.3.557.7; Envelope(s); Owens, Sarah Frances Alford, 1937-2015; NA (Folder First Day of Issue National Park Centennial Stamps)
  envelope shows a representation of the Cape Hatteras Lighthouse and a surfboat with USLS members in it
- First Day of Issue of National Parks Centennial Envelope and Postage Stamps, 5 April 1972; 113424; 33EPH-117-2; 5000.3.557.2; Envelope(s); Owens, Sarah Frances Alford, 1937-2015; NA (Folder First Day of Issue of National Parks Centennial Envelope and Postage Stamps)
- Invitation to Ceremony for the First Day of Issuance of the Cape Hatteras National Seashore Commemorative Stamps Honoring the National Parks Centennial Year, 4 May 1972; 113431; 33EPH-117-9; 5000.3.557.9; Ephemera, printed; Owens, Sarah Frances Alford, 1937-2015; NA (Folder Invitation to Ceremony for the First Day of Issuance of the Cape Hatteras National Seashore Commemorative Stamps Honoring the National Parks Centennial Year)
- First Day of Issue, US Postal Service, People Serving You, 30 April 1973; 113427; 33EPH-117-5; 5000.3.557.5; Envelope(s); Owens, Sarah Frances Alford, 1937-2015; NA (Folder First Day of Issue, US Postal Service, People Serving You)
  one 4 1/2 x 10 1/2 envelope with 10 stamps
- First Day of Issue Ceremony 21 Cent International Airmail Postal Card, 17 December 1975; 113433; 33EPH-117-12; 5000.3.557.11; Programs; Owens, Sarah Frances Alford, 1937-2015; NA (Folder First Day of Issue Ceremony 21 Cent International Airmail Postal Card)
- Envelope Commemorating Wright Brothers Flight with Stamps Commemorating the 50th Anniversary of Commercial Aviation, 17 December 1976; 113426; 33EPH-117-4; 5000.3.557.4; Envelope(s); Owens, Sarah Frances Alford, 1937-2015; NA (Folder Envelope Commemorating Wright Brothers Flight with Stamps Commemorating the 50th Anniversary of Commercial Aviation)